Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ sruthishyamsunder (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Algorithms
Python
Machine Learning

Languages

English (Full Professional)

Tamil (Native or Bilingual)

Telugu (Native or Bilingual)

Sruthi Shyamsunder

Data Scientist & Software Engineer

Orange County, California Area

Summary

I enjoy providing insights into data, developing data intensive software products and learning to develop machine learning models to automate solutions. I have an academic background in Computer Science & Networked Systems and professional experience in software development, predictive analytics & data engineering using technologies such as Python, Java, Linux, Hadoop, SQL and NoSQL databases.

Experience

Appriss

5 years

Senior Data Scientist & Software Engineer July 2019 - Present (9 months)

- Tech and project lead for key engineering initiatives in R&D Data Science division.
- Expanded data consolidation and search solutions to victim notification services (VINE), public safety and background screening applications.
- Technologies: AWS Cloud, Redshift, Aurora, SQS, Kinesis, S3, Kubernetes, Docker, Python, SQL.

Data Scientist & Software Engineer April 2015 - July 2019 (4 years 4 months) Irvine

Some of my projects include:

- Development of a data consolidation engine to connect relevant consumer records into graph networks.
- Feature engineering and development of consumer & employee fraud detection/prediction models for retail clients.
- Developing machine learning models to classify retail items based on description.

- Development of REST API for user search and data feed for data intensive applications hosted as micro services on docker containers.
- Data engineering and development of data pipelines for migration between HDFS and relational databases.
- ETL processing terabytes of retail transaction logs into HDFS.
- Data Analysis and Data Visualization.

Appriss Retail
Data Scientist Intern
January 2015 - March 2015 (3 months)
Irvine

- Analyzed consumer purchase and return behavior from retail data.
- Optimized a retail return authorization model in SAS to increase denials on odd and abusive consumer behavior.
- Estimated a 10% increase in dollars saved due to preventing fraudulent returns.

Appriss Retail
Data Scientist Intern
June 2014 - September 2014 (4 months)
Irvine

- Developed distributed algorithms to extract behavioral features and generate shopper profiles from retail transaction data to predict/detect fraud.
- The algorithms, implemented in Java, use Map-Reduce to scale billions of records on a Hadoop cluster.

UC Irvine Graduate Teaching Assistant April 2014 - June 2014 (3 months) Irvine

Computer Networking Teaching Assistant for undergraduate Computer Science and Computer Engineering majors.

California Plug Load Research Center Android Application developer April 2014 - June 2014 (3 months) Irvine.California

- Developed a sync framework to co-ordinate and automate data update/ transfer operations across Android devices and websites for the Wall Of Power (WoP) research project, which evaluates consumer electronic energy usage.
- Implementation: Java

DSSI Solutions Pvt Ltd India Intern- Software Engineering May 2011 - June 2011 (2 months)

- Configured a Linux cluster, evaluated its performance under different configurations and documented comparisons of different versions of Linux.
- Prepared a compatibility matrix for specific set of software with those Linux versions.

Education

University of California, Irvine Master's degree, Networked Systems · (2013 - 2015)

Anna University

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science · (2009 - 2013)